Vaibhav Mishra

Professional Summary

Experience in architecting and delivering large scale complex projects using web/mobile technologies, with in-depth knowledge of Solution Architecture.

Exposure in design and development of applications and possess knowledge of various languages, systems and databases, such as PHP, JavaScript, MySql, MongoDB, Micro Services, Elasticseach, Redis, CI/CD.

Equipped with the knowledge of various softwares, organizing technical demonstrations, with sound understanding of creating new software systems, designing, analysis, testing, developing modules and Resource allocation to meet customer's specific needs.

Self motivated and goal-oriented with a high degree of flexibility, creativity, resourcefulness, commitment and optimism.

SKILLS

- PHP
- Micro Service
- MongoDB
- Docker
- AWS
- Git
- CI/CD

- REST API
- SQL
- HTML
- Elastic Search
- Redis
- FFMPEG
- Linux

Experience

Modestreet Internet, Noida — Backend Developer

JULY 2017 - PRESENT

- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for this project.
- Build complete Backend in Micro Service & API structure.
- Build complete, secure, robust architecture for Backend.
- Used various technologies, including PHP, MongoDB, SQL, Elastic Search, AWS, Micro-Services, Docker,
 GitLab CI/CD to create this project.
- Created Independent Wrapper function and procedures for Data Collection in
 - o Magento-1
 - o Woocommerce
 - Magento-2 (Order Process)
 - o Payment Merchants
 - Delivery Partners
- Coordinated with project management staff on Project development timelines and project scope.
- Build new type of Social Networking Ecosystem structure.

Provensec LLC, Faridabad — Backend Developer

SEP 2016 - MAY 2017

 Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.

- Wrote highly maintainable, solid code in **laravel** for Backend system that formed core framework and has won consistent praise from subsequent developers since initial version.
- Installed and configured various Security software applications like **modsecurity, OpenSSH** and tested solutions for effectiveness.
- Created procedures for system monitoring, recovery, backup and optimization through **Munin and Cron**.

Viralcurry, New Delhi — Backend Developer

DEC 2015 - AUG 2016

- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Used various technologies, such as AWS, PHP, FFMPEG, REST API, SQL to build this Testify: Fun Video Editing and Social Networking Project.
- Took concepts and produced design mockups and prototypes to strengthen designs, enhance user experiences and improve App interactions.
- Build Fast **Uploading and Streaming Media** Structure.

Zenhancer Technology, NOIDA — *Developer*

SEP 2014 - MAY 2015

- Developed and implemented IIT-JEE E-Learning Project for all platform like Web App, Android App & Windows App for TATA McGraw Hill.
- Managed E-Learning technological issues for assigned projects, increasing customer rating 4.3 in Windows
 App.
- Coordinated with TATA McGraw Hill project head to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.
- Used various technologies, such as PHP, Adobe Flash Player, Adobe Reader

Education

SR Group Of Institutions, LUCKNOW — B-Tech

Computer Engineering Technology (2009 - 2013)

Achievements

- Handle TATA McGraw Hill Project as Technical head.
- Build Adapter for getting Data From 3rd Party API's.
- Create Social Networking and E-Commerce System in a project.
- Getting 0.23 Million Play Store Download in Testify Project.